(Amy)Ping-Ju Chen

(647) 870-6804 | Toronto, ON M2K 0B1

Email: pingjuchen423@gmail.com | GitHub: AmyRChen | LinkedIn: <a href="mailto:AmyRCh

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Enthusiastic recent graduate of Computer Programming seeking a position as a New Grad Full Stack Developer at CGI. Competent in coordination and system implementation with 2+ years of experience as business analyst in the Information Technology department of Deloitte. Hoping to apply my extensive knowledge of programming and problem-solving skills to bring forward actionable insights that deliver meaningful and sustainable outcomes.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Operating Systems: Linux, Windows 10, MacOS

• **Programming Languages:** Bash shell, C, C++, JavaScript, Python

Database Technologies: Oracle, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

• Web Development: HTML, CSS, Node.js, React, Bootstrap, Express.js, Next.js

• IDE, Code Editors: Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code

• Project Management Tools: Trello, MS Project, GitHub

EDUCATION

Computer Programming Diploma

2022 - Present

Seneca College, Toronto, ON

- Learned programming languages such as C, C++, Python and built projects.
- Gained fundamental knowledge of relational databases and NoSQL with hands-on exercises.
- Designed projects based on stakeholder requirements and applied SDLC processes.
- Collaborated with classmates to overcome obstacles and demonstrate products to clients.
- Applied data structure and algorithms to solve different needs.
- Named to President's Honor List.

Bachelor of Accountancy

2014 - 2018

Ming Chuan University, Taipei, Taiwan

- Obtained knowledge of examining financial records, evaluate risks, and abide tax laws.
- Learned calculus and statistics.

PROFESSIONAL PROJECTS

MERN - Social Media Web App

Used languages/ tools/ environment: MongoDB, Express.js, React, Node.js, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3

• A user-friendly full stack responsive MERN social media app with authorization and authentication, friends list, likes, dark mode, posts functions.

MyBlog Web App

Used languages/ tools/ environment: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, JSON, MongoDB, Bootstrap, Handlebars, Cyclic

• A published blog web application with registration/log-in and account, create/read/update/

delete posts and images functions.

For more details of these projects and other academic projects, please visit my GitHub page.

EXPERIENCE

Business Analyst 2019 - 2021

Deloitte, Taipei, Taiwan

- Consulted in the digital transformation of the audit and financial report preparation process, booted efficiency by 83%. Ensured user-friendly, straightforward software interface.
- Counseled for Audit& Assurance team with Financial Report System in internal training events. Assisted in application-level support.
- Collaborated with stakeholders, lead the projects of Audit & Assurance department.
- Negotiated between stakeholders and raised actionable insights.
- Performed System integration testing (SIT) to ensure all parts of the project successfully co-exist and exchange data where necessary.
- Organized several meetings based on SDLC stages, including a discussion of User Acceptance Testing (UAT).
- Launched the workload management system, effectively helped the Quality Risk Management department to improve budget control time by 68%.
- Participated in global system introduction as a data team member. Operated data migration in several scopes. Tested data creation with various multiple teams, and logged any defects found, contributing to the successful testing and quality assurance for system.
- Managed work arrangements and provided system training and support for more than 20 interns.

Auditor 2018 - 2019

Deloitte, Taipei, Taiwan

- Audited internal control procedures and issued the related report for more than 3 clients.
- Inspected accounting records and financial documents to ensure accuracy and with the law.
- Examined and analyzed accounting records to determine financial status and prepare financial reports for clients with a net worth of more than 14 billion US dollars.
- Assisted in declaring business income tax and issuing tax reports for more than 5 clients.

Audit Intern 2017 - 2018

Deloitte, Taipei, Taiwan

- Examined journal entries testing for several clients.
- Discovered unusual financial entries and reported to Audit & Assurance department.

Financial Intern 2017 - 2017

L'Occitane en Provence, Taipei, Taiwan

- Assisted all stores in daily journal entries key-in.
- Collected operational and market data for financial analysis.

References available upon request.